All right. So, you now know how to
create elements and add them to the
page. So, if I asked you to, you could
probably make it so that this form would
work. So, you can enter names, titles,
you can upload a picture, and then click
add dog, and it would add it to this
page. You'd also probably think that
that might be a lot of quite a bit of a
pain. Like, let's for example, let's
inspect this one. So we can see that
it's in a div that has the class of card
which means we would need to create a
div element and assign it a class of
card. Then we'd need to create an image
tag and assign both its alt and its
source. Um
we'd also need to create another div
called info and we would need to put um
a p tag in it. We'd need to set the pt
tags class and we'd need to set the pt
tags inner text. We'd also need to set
the title and inner text. And that's
another P tag. That's a lot of elements
to create. And that might sound like a
pain just to add a single card here like
these cards. And I want to show you how
you can get around that. Wouldn't it be
nice if there was just a nice neat
template where you could just inject the
things that you wanted and then add it
to the page? Well, there is. The way you
do that is you use what's called a
template tag. So I'm going to come over
to my HTML
and I'm going to add a template tag. So
right here I'm going to type the word
template
and this is an HTML tag. The nice thing
about template tags is that they are
inert or in other words you cannot edit
them using JavaScript. They are read
only which means that crossite scripting
attacks don't work on a template tag
directly. They cannot target your
template tag, which means anything you
read out of the template tag will be as
you've set it up in the template tag.
So, I have this HTML that I am
consistently putting out. So, let's take
this div and copy it and we'll put it in
our template tag. Okay. So, we know that
on the screen we're going to be
repeatedly adding a div with the class
of card.
The source, well, we're going to change
the source. Um,
the name we're going to change the
title, we're going to change. We should
probably also change the alt. So, when
we put this on screen, we want to change
those. So, we have now successfully
created a template. And the nice thing
about a template is if we reload this
page, template's nowhere to be seen. We
put it directly after this last input,
nowhere on screen. And that is because
templates are hidden by default from the
user. And we will pick up in the next